# **Gregory Strom**

## Full Stack Web Developer

Web developer with 11 years of experience redeploying exceptional communication and analytic skills honed as a University-level teacher of philosophy and logic. Extensive international experience collaborating with students and colleagues to solve conceptual problems and make exciting ideas work.

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

## University of Pittsburgh, Department of Physics & Astronomy

Administrative Secretary | September 2019 - present | Pittsburgh

 Created, maintained and updated the "Coffee House" website facilitating international collaboration between chemists and physicists on groundbreaking research publications

#### Math-M-Addicts

Assistant Teacher | September 2020 - present | New York

 Used web-based education technology to teach weekly courses on advanced math concepts for children ages 10-12, with autonomy and responsibility gradually increasing to include multiple courses and independent teaching

## University of Pittsburgh, Department of Philosophy

Website Manager, Visiting Lecturer/Instructor | 2011, 2013 – 2021 | Pittsburgh

- Taught myself HTML & CSS to maintain and update faculty supervisor's academic website, augmenting availability of his research to colleagues
- Reinstated and organized annual Visitors' Conference, permanently enriching Department culture by establishing international professional relationships between philosophers in 6 universities
- Enhanced Department's teaching capability by adventurously expanding teaching repertoire to include 9 new subjects, crafting syllabuses and delivering lectures for 27 undergraduate and 17 adult education courses
- Supervised and evaluated teams of 2-4 teaching assistants

## Carnegie Mellon University, Department of Philosophy

Special Faculty | August 2019 – December 2020 | Pittsburgh

 Created syllabuses and delivered lectures for undergraduate courses covering topics at the intersection of philosophy & technology (AI, engineering ethics, etc.)

## University of Sydney, Centre for Time

Postdoctoral Fellow | July 2011 – July 2013 | Sydney, Australia

 Coordinated weekly international guest speaker program while supervising graduate level dissertation project and instructing graduate seminars

## **PROJECTS**

Meet App | https://gbstrom.github.io/meet/

 Serverless PWA hosted on Amazon Lambda that works with Google Calendar API and login handled by Google OAuth2. Built with HTML, CSS, JS, React

myFlix API & Angular client | https://gbstrom.github.io/myFlix-Angular-client/

• Angular front-end client for back-end movie API built with JS, MongoDB

gbstrom@gmail.com +1-412-759-4591 Pittsburgh, PA, USA github.com/gbstrom linkedin.com/in/gbstrom gbstrom.github.io/portfolio/

### **SKILLS**

- HTML
- CSS
- JavaScript
- MongoDB
- Node
- React
- React Native
- React Bootstrap
- Configuring Heroku
- Amazon Web Services
- Angular
- Angular Material
- Git
- Responsive Design
- jQuery
- Test Driven Development

#### **EDUCATION**

## Certificate in Full Stack Web Development

CareerFoundry - online May 2021 – March 2022

#### PhD in Philosophy

University of Pittsburgh August 2003 – August 2011

#### **BA in Philosophy**

University of Chicago September 1998 – June 2002

#### RESEARCH

'Deviant Causal Chains, Knowledge of Reasons, and *Akrasia*'

Published in *Topoi*, April 2014

'Multitasking, Consequentialism and Practical Imagination'

PhD Thesis University of Pittsburgh, 2011